welcome back to my channel today we're
doing the easiest fringe earrings
and here's everything you need to get
started
miyuki beads are essential for this
tutorial
to get started grab your needle and some
thread we're going to need about four
feet or around a meter to thread my
needle i hold the thread in my
non-dominant hand and use my dominant
hand to direct the needle and it's a lot
easier pull the thread through so the
needle is halfway and it is all folded
over then we're going to wax one end of
the thread so we're going to grab one
foot of the end like so and just wax
that section
and now we can get started with brick
stitch so we're going to grab four beads
on our needle to get started
then carefully pull the beads down the
needle and thread until you get near the
end but make sure to leave yourself a
few inch tail
and then i'm going to put my needle
through the first two beads like so so
we create a loop so the two beads are in
two rows next to each other
then we're going to make sure that tail
is about four to six inches long you
don't want it too short
then to finish this first section we're
going to put our needle down through the
beads next to where it already was like
so so now both our threads are coming
out the bottom of the bead
and then we can go ahead and add two at
a time to start our base row
then i'm going to go through the beads
like so creating a circle with my thread
as you can see it's looping around
so i'm putting my needle in the opposite
end where the thread is coming out
and then when you pull it you'll see
that the two beads should again sit next
to the other two beads then go up those
two beads and that's how we add on to
our first row
build the base row two beads at a time
repeating these same steps again and
again until we have a
base row that is seven beads across
like this
another recommended step is to then go
back through all of your beads to help
them be extra secure
so i'm just weaving back and forth on
our base row to get it nice and stiff
and then we can start our next row
whenever we start a new row we're going
to start with double the beads so i'm
going to grab four beads to continue our
double stack pattern
then our next row we are going to use
these stitches between the beads as our
anchor so you can see first stitch
second stitch i'm going to go through
the second stitch since we have double
the beads and we're starting a new row
so just pull like so and you'll see
they're kind of sitting nicely now put
your needle through the last two
and you'll see that they create our new
row an optional step i do is i secure
with an extra stitch so i go back down
through the other beads and then up
through the beads on the right side
like so
i find this makes it look a little bit
extra perfect which if you're a
perfectionist you'll love if you're
looking for speed you can just skip that
step
for the remainder of the row we'll go
two beads at a time and we're going to
go through the next loop the
we only skip when we are doing the first
beads on the row from here we're going
to do two at a time and it's going to be
through the next available stitch now
just keep on doing your brick stitch
until we get to the top when we have a
three bead row just like this one so you
can see it's three double stacks now you
can either do four beads as your hook or
you can use a thread protector or wire
guard like i am here so i'll show you
how to use it just put your needle up
through one side and then over down the
other side into the brick stitch
like so
and i like to use these because they are
extra secure whereas sometimes your
earring hook can fall off of the
beadwork if you don't have a wire guard
make sure the thread is sitting in that
guarded area and not falling out this
will make sure it is fully secured then
i'm going to weave my way down to the
base row so we can add our fringe
and we've done all the hard steps now
it's time for the quick easy final step
then i'm going to use my pattern to map
out my fringe go check out my last video
if you want to learn how to do this
and then we can get started this way i
know exactly how many beads i need for
each row
all counted out and ready to go so
following the pattern i need to grab
five beads one silver bead and then
alternate colors and then finally with
the last section to add ten
use a piece of paper to cover the rest
of your pattern so you can focus one
fringe at a time
once your fringe is done move one bead
away and then go up the rest of the
beads and the two beads in your base row
then pull your needle through and all of
your thread
so your fringe is nicely secured and
pull any excess thread out but try not
to pull too tight
then you're going to go down the next
bead in our base row
go down and pull a little bit snugger
here
there you go and now repeat this with
the remaining fringes
then we just have the final step of
tying our thread off
if you're liking this video please give
it a thumbs up and make sure to
subscribe to see more of my videos
two-thirds of you guys watching aren't
subscribed so please make sure to do so
it really helps out my channel and i
would super appreciate it thank you
let's get back to the video
now that we finished our final fringe
we're going to take our thread and just
continue to weave it through the brick
stitch section of our earring
so you can see i'm working my way up and
then i want to create kind of a zigzag
pattern check out the example on screen
to see what i mean and then just trim
off the excess and repeat the same step
with the tail that you have remaining
from the beginning of the project
now all you have to do is add the
earring hook and the earrings are done i
just use my pliers open it up and pop it
right onto the thread protector
boom and they are nice and secure they
will not fall off these hooks
it's super easy this took me about 20
minutes to make this earring it
shouldn't take you too long and i'm sure
that you will do a great job and make
something beautiful thank you so much
for watching please give this video a
thumbs up and subscribe as always have a
beautiful day
you